hey there e-commerce business owners
have you ever found yourself puzzled
about the differences between buy costs
and landed costs in today's video we'll
unravel the differences between buy
costs and landed costs and we'll also
follow a product through its shipment
process so that you can see where those
costs come into play I'm Kelly from
leder gurus and we are all about
e-commerce accounting now we understand
that this process can be a little bit
tricky and we're here to guide you buy
costs are your starting point they are
the initial cost of purchasing the
product essentially they are the price
tag from your supplier last costs on the
other hand are the total costs of your
product once it reaches your Warehouse
it adds things like shipping and customs
and taxes and fees and all of that to
sum up buy costs are just the beginning
but landed costs follow the entire
journey of your product from the
supplier to your Warehouse understanding
buy costs and landed costs for
businesses is crucial and here's why
first it allows for detailed tracking of
expenses ensuring an accurate profit
margin this helps to determine which
ones are your most profitable products
second it aids in competitive pricing
strategies especially for those sourcing
globally this is vital to factor in all
of these costs lastly it's key for
strategic sourcing knowing your costs
can lead to better negotiations and
strategic sourcing in short mastering
these costs is essential for a healthy
bottom line and long-term business
success let's visualize this with a
story imagine a product say an
Electronics Gadget and we are going to
follow its progress from the supplier
all the way to the warehouse so it
starts at the supplier location where
the product is manufactured or sourced
for our story the initial buy cost is
$100 for 100 gadgets totaling
$10,000 the product is then manufactured
and packaged at the supplier's facility
at this point there's no added costs
next the product is transported to the
nearest chipping Port we're going to say
that this transport cost is about $500
to transport all1 ,000 gadgets at the
Customs checkout our product goes
through clearance and at this point we
are getting a hefty Customs fee of
$1,000 our product then embarks on its
International Journey being loaded into
a container ship the international
shipping cost is going to set us back
about another $2,000 upon reaching the
destination country's Port now it goes
through another round of customs and
fees and this is going to cost us about
another
$5,000 finally our product arrives at
the warehouse the transportation cost
from the port to the warehouse is $1,000
and then the warehouse has to receive it
and that's going to cost us about
another $500 and there you have it
that's how our product incurs all of its
landed costs as it moves from the
supplier to the warehouse so do you want
some help in being able to figure out
where all of these costs are coming from
and being able to pull it all into one
place we have an inventory and cogs
template and it's a free download that
you can then input all of these costs in
and it can bring it together and help
you to get accurate land costs also if
you're interested in implementing an
inventory management system we can help
you with that too and that's a wrap on
the differences between buy costs and
landed costs if that was helpful for you
make sure that you give us a thumbs up
and subscribe for more e-commerce
insights